

Brands worked on

FMCG







Jumside





FINTECH







multipie

BANKING







F COMMERCE

meesho

CONSUMER TECH





OTHERS







Skills

- Pan-India Campaign management
- Creativity and Problem-solving
- Client Relationship Management
- Project and Timeline Management
- Consultative Solution Selling
- Communication Skills
- **Detail Oriented Approach**
- Interpersonal Skills

Amit Saikia

Account Management | Advertising | Project Management | | B2B Sales | B2C Sales

Profile

MBA and Engineer with 7.5 years of work experience. Worked predominantly in Advertising with stints in D2C Sales and B2B sales. I have worked on successful projects spanning across Fintech, Ed-tech, Social Commerce, Banking and FMCG brands on projects involving Communications, Brand Strategy, Product Design, App interventions, UI UX designing and New Product Development. Worked in Ed-Tech and SaaS IT Solutions Sectors previously.

Work Experience



Heather May 2024 - Present Heather Grey

Global Marketing Specialist

- Executing marketing plans for current and new products in markets as well as in developing marketing programs to promote products
- Present research results and recommendations to the upper management team to help their decision-making.
- Data collection and analysis for strategic market segments, related to current and potential customers, and competitors
- Updating marketing content and sales supporting materials to ensure that the information is accurate, up to date, well organized, according to defined brand guidelines, and easily accessible to existing and potential customers
- Coordinate, assist, evaluate and approve work with agencies to showcase products, values and other creatives on company socials and improve overall SEO of our website
- Coordinating and organizing B2B events such as trade show events and customer surveys. Arrange schedules for attendees and extend customer invitations.
- Conduct post-event follow-up with attendees, leads, and potential customers to gather feedback, address inquiries, and nurture relationships.
- Implementing lead generation to assist the Sales team
- Contact vendors to prepare for marketing events
- Prepare promotional materials to showcase products
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to gather relevant data and insights for accurate forecasting
- Assist in Determining optimal inventory levels for various products or services based on demand forecasts and lead times
- Create valuable insights regarding demand variability, anticipated promotions, and upcoming product launches that may impact the supply chain
- · Monitor and Track actual sales performance against forecasted demand and identify areas of improvement



Feb 2019 - Apr 2024 Sideways

Senior Account Manager

- Collaborated with clients to develop advertising strategies and campaign objectives to assist with campaign development and execution
- Managed the creation of campaign assets, including sets of films and other materials tailored to different geographies





FMCG













FINTECH







multipie

BANKING







E COMMERCE

meesho

CONSUMER TECH





OTHERS







Skills

- Pan-India Campaign management
- Creativity and Problem-solving
- Client Relationship Management
- Project and Timeline Management
- Consultative Solution Selling
- Communication Skills
- **Detail Oriented Approach**
- Interpersonal Skills



Feb 2019 - Apr 2024 Sideways

Senior Account Manager

-CONT'D

- Ensuring consistency and alignment of messaging and visuals across various regions
- Involved with execution and pan-national delivery of Creatives across TV, Digital, Print, Outdoor, Instore and Out-of-store, packaging, social media posts for different clients
- Assisting delivery of Strategic insight Development, Positioning and Brand Identity Development (Guidelines, Tone of Voice, Visual and Sonic identity
- Jointly developing the Creative Brief collaboratively with the client and briefing internal teams
- Overseeing multiple projects simultaneously, ensuring timely delivery and adherence to budgets.
- Development and management of project timelines, milestones, and deliverables
- Cross-functional coordination across multiple hierarchies and stakeholders
- New business proposal development, negotiation and solutioning based on problems presented by clients
- Preparation and delivery of presentations to clients
- Maintaining detailed meeting records, extracting key action points, coordination and management of subsequent activities
- Selection, negotiation and co-ordination with vendors for various services including production houses, artwork and design studios, research agencies and translation agencies
- Conducting research to understand target audiences in different geographies and analyze market trends and consumer behavior to inform campaign strategies
- New business development activities, identifying areas for cross selling and upselling
- Handled business worth approx. INR 6-7 Cr during tenure
- Wide exposure to various different projects including UI/UX Interventions and designs for universities and fintech apps
- Assisting with Prototyping and development of 3D concepts for new product ideas
- Developed customer acquisition-based app interventions and communication



Mar 2018-Jan 2019 Think and Learn Pvt. Ltd. - BYJU'S

Business Development Associate

- Sales funnel management and scheduling in person home visits for sales calls with prospects via telecall
- Demonstrated knowledge for selling techniques of mathematics and science to prospects to showcase effectiveness of product.
- Pitching the product and addressing queries and concerns raised during sales calls
- Demonstrating applicability of various product features and explaining fit with child's educational requirements
- Doubt solving and management of student issues via calls and images over text
- Exhibiting emotional intelligence during pitches so as to keep visits polite and professional
- Conversion of leads into customers via in-person home visits to customers.
- Seeking references from converted customers
- Management of course fees for parents, routing payments through multiple financial instruments

Education

- NMIMS, Mumbai (2015-17)
 MBA Sales and Marketing
- RGIT, Mumbai (2010-14)
 B.E. Instrumentation
- Bhavans College, Mumbai (2008-10)12th HSC PCME
- Maneckji Cooper, Mumbai (2008)
 10th ICSE Science

Contact

- amitsaikia21@gmail.com
- 9819835150
- Marol, Andheri East, Mumbai



May 2017-Feb 2018 Writer Information

Senior Sales Executive

- Responsible for sales of DMS and HIMS solutions across Bangalore, Mysore, Mangalore and Manipal
- Setting up meetings with prospect stakeholders and conducting sales visits with prospects
- Pitching products to various stakeholders amongst prospects from telecom, healthcare, BFSI, Insurance and other sectors
- Conducting thorough product demonstrations and discussing module-wise solutions as per prospect requirements
- Funnel management and communication with prospect organisations
- Conducting demonstrations of HIMS software and discussing solutioning as per individual client requirements

NAMASTE Apr 2016 - May 2016
CREDIT Namaste Credit

Summer Intern

- Developed and implemented methods of channel partner acquisition to register partners with Namaste Credit
- Studied consumer behavior as well as channel partner behavior to gain a better understanding of target market
- Made recommendations for strategic changes in operations to improve overall efficiency in channel partner acquisition
- Developed content for digital marketing campaign and recommended marketing channels for the same
- Carried out digital competitive benchmarking of Namaste Credit and its competitors for various digital parameters



Dec 2014- May 2015 Cutting Edge Events

Junior Operations Executive

- Interacted with clients from initial stages of travel package design up to the final package handover
- Designed and implemented packages for the ICC Cricket World Cup 2015
- Handled ticket booking for the IPL 2015 and conception and handovers for Free Independent Travel
- · Assisted with invoicing, billing of clients and verification of payments